
<module>
  <name>strategy/general/rename</name>
  <description><![CDATA[
                        Renaming of bound variables is determined by the shape of
                        variables and binding constructs. Three generic strategies
                        are defined that cater for different complexities of binding
                        constructs.
                        
                        Variable binding constructs protect variables from clashing
                        with variables in other parts of a program when their names
                        are the same. To prevent the introduction of name clashes
                        during program transformation it can be useful to give
                        all variable bindings a unique name. This module defines three
                        generic strategies for bound variable renaming all based on
                        the same idea, but dealing with increasingly complex variable
                        binding models.
                        
                        Renaming depends \emph{only} on the shape of variable bindings
                        and variable occurences. Other language constructs are irrelevant.
                        
                        In the generic strategies the following assumptions about
                        binding constructs are made: (1)
                        There is a subtree that covers the scope in which the
                        variables are bound. (2) variables are atomic, i.e., do not
                        contain subterms that are
                        variables or binding constructs.
                        
                        Approach: indicate shape of variable occurences and variable
                        binders
                        
                        ]]></description>
  
  
  
  <strategy>
    <name>rename</name>
    <description><![CDATA[
                          renaming bound variables assuming that variables are bound
                          in all subterms of a binding construct
                          variable declarations in binding constructs are assumed to
                          have the same shape as variable uses
                          
                          ]]></description>
    <start>55</start>
    <end>60</end>
    
    
  </strategy>
  
  
  <strategy>
    <name>rename</name>
    <description><![CDATA[
                          The strategy \verb|rename(isvar, mkvar, bnd)| renames all
                          bound variables in a term to fresh variables;
                          
                          Parameters:
                          
                          isvar: Succeeds if applied to a variable
                          newvar: Takes a string and builds a variable
                          bnd: Maps a binding construct to the list of bound variables
                          
                          renaming while making a distinction between subterms
                          in which the variables are bound or not
                          variables at binding sites are assumed to have
                          the same shape as other variable occurences
                          
                          ]]></description>
    <start>86</start>
    <end>92</end>
    
    
  </strategy>
  
</module>
